Hello and welcome to a little snapshot into our lives as two people who hate
meal prepping in the typical sense but have really fallen in love with cooking.
So yeah, here's almost everything we prepped and enjoyed this week in our cosy little
apartment.
The food week for us tends to start on a Saturday morning.
We're big market people, so once we've brainstormed our menu for the week, we try
to get out the door as quickly as possible.
As always the first stop for us is a bakery and this one is one
of our favorites.
Then it's straight to the markets to do the rest of our shop.
so
we
just got back from Queen Victoria Market we had a very successful haul this morning
we haven't been home for a week so I think we're very much in a
cooking mood starting off with our veggies.
We have some kale, we've got some choi sum, spring onions, coriander and mint which
we'll use in a biryani that we're going to make tomorrow night as well as
all these onions which will be used in it as well.
Some cucumbers, some spinach up the back here and we've really been getting into making
gimbap at the moment which our friends taught us and then for fruit we've got
grapes, We've got these beautiful white peaches over here.
And then down the bottom there, we just have some tomatoes, lemon and some potatoes.
Next up, we've got our beautiful loaf of white sourdough.
Down there, we've got our eggs, which we also got from the markets.
Then finally, we have some spicy sausages here.
We have this stunning snapper.
We've got two different cuts of chicken.
We have Maryland pieces, which we'll use for the biryani.
and then we've got drumstick pieces and actually we didn't get those drumsticks from the
markets we got those ones from Woolies they're actually really cheap at Woolies.
Okay so how much did everything cost?
Starting off with the bread this loaf cost us eight dollars which is pretty standard
I think and it's really great bread so we're definitely not unhappy about that.
Then in terms of the protein these sausages over here cost us ten dollars the
snapper was twenty The Maryland pieces of chicken were $12 and the drumsticks were $5, which, yeah,
that's really, really cheap for chicken.
The eggs over there, they cost us $8 for that carton, and all of the fruit
and veggies combined cost us $36.55.
So the total of this week's shop came to $109.55, which is definitely
not too bad for the amount of amazing produce we got.
It's snapper boy.
We've been trying to cook a bit more fish lately.
That's a big fish.
It's an area that we feel like we still have a lot to learn about.
We went with the whole snapper.
It's kind of a versatile fish and it's a bit cheaper than buying fillets.
Today we stuffed it with some dill and leaven then chucked it in the oven
to have alongside some other leftovers.
These look slightly diabolical but these are my midnight pearl roasted potatoes.
I haven't actually roasted them yet, I've just parboiled them.
I part one of them to an inch of their life so you know it's
a learning experience
I like
the same genre
so we're back in the kitchen it's Monday night and we're making
dinner it's aggressively chopping up some chicken next to me we're making a chicken biryani
and we're making a kale molong which is like a kale salad.
Would you say like a Sri Lankan kale salad?
Yeah.
But it's a cooked salad.
Anything you want to say about the biryani?
It's a biryani recipe that I've kind of made up.
But where'd you get it from?
I actually got it from a Bon Appetit video where I watched chef go to
a street vendor selling biryani and I kind of just watched that video and interpreted
it.
I could watch that video and I would remember again and never get sick of
That is for sure.
Alright.
Try a good part of the biryani.
Honestly, it is the egg.
Yeah!
It's the egg.
I mean, no, no, but like, it's the egg combined with everything else.
I think the egg and the rice for me.
Um...
Can't go wrong with it.
Yeah.
All it's worth and all you want is egg and rice.
It's crazy.
Cool.
So, for you, that means...
I forget that.
🎵 Oh that's a perfect egg.
Alright, final product, chicken biryani.
This is our Monday night dinner.
We've got kale malung, a made up biryani recipe, boiled egg, and some yogurt and
some lemon to just squeeze.
Good?
Oh yeah.
Hello, it's Tuesday morning and it's like almost time to start work but we're about
to have breakfast and we have something really exciting today which is hot cross buns
because it's almost Easter time.
They also came with...
Pepper seya butter which is a really amazing butter that we have in Australia.
You only really find it at very bougie places.
We're gonna toast this bad boy up.
It's gonna be good.
Alright, do it.
Alright.
One each?
Yeah.
This makes me so happy.
It goes on pretty easily.
Oh.
On the pan really.
It's out of tube.
Oh yeah, that hits the spot.
Oh my gosh.
Maybe a bit more butter?
Yeah, a bit more butter.
It's
the middle of the week, so tonight we're doing something really simple.
We've found some amazing lore with the recipes recently and it's nice to know that
we can still cook up something comforting during the week without it feeling like a
huge undertaking or feeling like we have to rely on prepping everything in advance.
So yeah, on the menu for tonight is a simple chicken noodle soup.
To cook this we boil up some chicken stock then add in some chicken drumsticks.
Then once they're done you take them out and season the broth to add more
depth and flavour.
We're finishing this up by cooking choy sum in the broth and serving it all
up with noodles, fresh coriander and chilli.
We got this one from Cookbook.
What's the book?
The book is called Lana.
I'm not too sure how to pronounce it.
It's a northern Thai cookbook that our friends gave us for Christmas.
And we've been cooking a lot of good things from here.
Mmm.
Yum.
That broth's good.
Smells good?
Yeah.
Alright.
Mmm.
This morning we're both working from home, so we've got a bit more time to
prep lunch while we eat breakfast.
Today's lunch is Gimbap, which is a green seaweed rice roll, and actually a recent
addition to our cooking repertoire when our friends packed it for us on a hike
last year.
All I can remember thinking while we were walking was how excited I was to
stop for lunch and finally get to try it.
And it didn't disappoint.
Since then, our friends graciously took the time to teach us and it's been on
rotation a lot.
What I really love about it is that it's so rewarding to make.
It has quite a few elements but when you finally roll them all together and
see your fully formed kimbap it feels like all your hard work has paid off.
Alright, it's Friday and on Fridays we'll usually cook up a meat that we had
frozen earlier in the week as none of the fresh stuff would typically last until
then.
So tonight we're making a creamy sausage pasta.
This recipe really hits the spot.
It's saucy, savoury, spicy and there's kale in it which gives it a great crunch
that you don't always get in a pasta dish.
It's a lovely way to end what was already a really good week of eating.
Oh
yeah it is reggaete.
In this sausage pasta we have sausages, there's kale, there's cream, passata, some chili,
some arugano.
It's really really simple and I'm actually sick today so this was kind of the
perfect thing that I really needed.
Thanks so much for sticking around and watching this little peek into a food week
for us.
We're hoping to create some more videos around what we like to cook and our
journey learning about food in general.
So if this interests you, subscribe to our channel and we'll hopefully see you in
the next one!